A Guide to the Papers of Elizabeth Oakes Prince Smith, 1823-1894
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Literary Manuscripts
  - Manuscript Poems by Elizabeth Oakes Smith: A-Z, 2 folders ca. 1860-1893 (Box 2)
  - Manuscript Poems by Elizabeth Oakes Smith: Sonnets ca. 1860-1893 (Box 2)
  - Manuscript Poems by Elizabeth Oakes Smith: Untitled ca. 1860-1893 (Box 2)
  - Manuscript Poems by Elizabeth Oakes Smith: Fragments n.d. (Box 2)
  - Poems by Elizabeth Oakes Smith Printed in Newspaper and Journals, 2 folders ca. 1860-1893 (Box 2)
  - Speeches and Lectures by Elizabeth Oakes Smith: "Biology and Woman's Rights" 1879 (Box 2)
  - Speeches and Lectures by Elizabeth Oakes Smith: "Cleopatra" 1853 (Box 2)
  - Speeches and Lectures by Elizabeth Oakes Smith: "The Dignity of Labor" n.d. (Box 2)
  - Speeches and Lectures by Elizabeth Oakes Smith: "Funeral of Mrs. Fay" 1877 (Box 2)
  - Speeches and Lectures by Elizabeth Oakes Smith: "Margaret Fuller" 1851 (Box 2)
  - Speeches and Lectures by Elizabeth Oakes Smith: "Our Humanity" 1851 (Box 2)
  - Speeches and Lectures by Elizabeth Oakes Smith: "Womanhood" 1851 (Box 2)
  - Reviews of Lectures by Elizabeth Oakes Smith ca. 1851-1857 (Box 2)
  - Essays by Elizabeth Oakes Smith: "Books," "Girls of Long Ago," "History of the Amazons," and "Machinito" 1870-1887, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Essays by Elizabeth Oakes Smith: " Mem[o]s," "James Sargent Osgood," "The Poet," and "St. Valentines" 1870-1887, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Essays by Elizabeth Oakes Smith: "Three Queens," "The Two Wives," and "Woman the Inferior" 1870-1887, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Essays by Elizabeth Oakes Smith: "The First Bond," untitled 1870-1879, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Plays by Elizabeth Oakes Smith: Roman Tributeca. 1850 (Box 3)
  - Plays by Elizabeth Oakes Smith: Old New York or Democracy in 1689, includes notes 1853 (Box 3)
  - Plays by Elizabeth Oakes Smith: Destiny(two manuscript copies, 1 manuscript bound) n.d. (Box 3)
  - Short story by Elizabeth Oakes Smith: "Luck at the Crossroads" n.d. (Box 3)
  - Short story by Elizabeth Oakes Smith: "The Destiny" n.d. (Box 3)
  - Short story by Elizabeth Oakes Smith: Untitled Fragments n.d. (Box 3)
  - Novella by Elizabeth Oakes Smith: Untitled n.d. (Box 3)
  - Novel by Elizabeth Oakes Smith: The Queen of Trumpsn.d. (Box 3)
  - Novel by Elizabeth Oakes Smith: Untitled n.d. (Box 3)
  - Sermons by Elizabeth Oakes Smith, 3 folders 1872, 1877 Mar-Dec, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Diary of Elizabeth Oakes Smith 1861 Oct-1865 Mar (Box 4)
  - Diary/Journal of Elizabeth Oakes Smith 1865 Mar-Apr (Box 4)
  - Diary of Elizabeth Oakes Smith (includes newspaper clippings and correspondence) 1866 Jul 28-1868 Mar 4 (Box 4)
  - Journal of Elizabeth Oakes Smith (includes poems) 1877-1879 (Box 4)
  - Newspaper Columns by Elizabeth Oakes Smith re travel and geography (printed) ca. 1853-1868 (Box 4)
  - Newspaper Columns by Elizabeth Oakes Smith re woman's rights, marriage, family and child rearing (printed) ca. 1855-1886 (Box 4)
  - Newspaper Columns by Elizabeth Oakes Smith re Public correspondence with "Mary Forrest" [Julia Deane Freeman} (printed) 1856 (Box 4)
  - Newspaper Columns by Elizabeth Oakes Smith re suffrage for women and negroes (printed) ca. 1868-1890 (Box 4)
  - Newspaper Columns by Elizabeth Oakes Smith re literary subjects (printed) ca. 1878-1886 (Box 4)
  - Newspaper Columns by Elizabeth Oakes Smith re "Kitty Howard's Journal" (printed) n.d. (Box 5)
  - Newspaper Columns by Elizabeth Oakes Smith re religious subjects (printed) n.d. (Box 5)
  - Misc. Newspaper Columns by Elizabeth Oakes Smith including book reviews (printed) n.d. (Box 5)
  - Notes by Elizabeth Oakes Smith re Shakespeare n.d. (Box 5)
  - Manuscript Fragments by Elizabeth Oakes Smith n.d. (Box 5)
  - Manuscript Poems by Seba Smith ante 1868 (Box 5)
  - Poems Printed in Newspapers by Seba Smith ante 1868 (Box 5)
  - Book of Verse by Seba Smith 1862-1863 (Box 5)
  - "Scattered waifs of half a century" by Seba Smith, contains poems, and commentaries on the poem of others 1867 (Box 5)
  - Short stories by Seba Smith ante 1868 (Box 5)
  - Lists of persons receiving author's copy of New Elements of Geometry by Seba Smith ca. 1851 (Box 5)
  - Reviews of lectures re New Elements of Geometry at Brooklyn Academy, Female Academy (Brooklyn), Westminister Hall (Providence, R.I.), and University Chapel (New York City) ca. 1851 (Box 5)
  - Lecture re New Elements of Geometry at the American Institute (New York City), with printed reviews ca. 1851 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence with John Parker re New Elements of Geometry, with printed reviews by John Parker ca. 1851 (Box 5)
  - Book Reviews by Professor Elias Loomis re New Elements of Geometryca. 1851 (Box 5)
  - Book Reviews of New Elements of Geometryca. 1851 (Box 5)
  - Newspaper Columns by Seba Smith re "Life of Major Jack Downing" ca. 1833-1846 (Box 5)
  - Newspaper Columns by Seba Smith re "Life of Solomon Swop" 1853 (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous Newspaper Columns by Seba Smith ante 1868 (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous Book Reviews of My Thirty Years out of the Senate by Jack Downing [Seba Smith] 1859 (Box 5)
  - Poems by Alvin Oaksmith 1876 Dec 27 (Box 5)
  - Two notebooks containing poems and short stories by Appleton Oaksmith 1856, 1965 (Box 5)
  - Poems, essays, short story, pamphlets by Appleton Oaksmith 1857-1877, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Poem by Aurora Oaksmith 1884 May 24 (Box 5)
  - Diary of Bessie Oaksmith 1873 (Box 5)
  - Poems and essays by Bessie Oaksmith 1873, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Poems by Corinne Oaksmith 1878-1879 (Box 5)
  - Journal of Edward Oaksmith 1855-1856 (Box 5)
  - Diary of Edward Oaksmith (includes letters, poems and short stories) 1857 Sep-1859 Nov (Box 6)
  - The Miser by Moliere translated by Edward Oaksmith and J. G. Methua 1863 (Box 6)
  - Poems, lectures and short stories by Edward Oaksmith ante 1865 (Box 6)
  - Poems by "Raymond" [Edward Oaksmith] n.d. (Box 6)
  - Poem by Sidney Oaksmith ante 1869 (Box 6)
  - Phrenological Character Analyses of Sidney Oaksmith 1859, 1866 (Box 6)
  - French Passport of Sidney Oaksmith 1860 (Box 6)
  - Novella: "Captain Mack, A Story of the Great Rebellion" (author unknown) n.d. (Box 6)
  - Play: "Hermance, the child of Fortune" (author unknown) n.d. (Box 6)
  - Short Story: "Annals of a Monkey" by Cousin Annie n.d. (Box 6)
  - Untitled Short Story (author unknown) n.d. (Box 6)
  - Poems by Mary Forrest, Paul H[amilton] Hayne, Herbert Moore, Frances Osgood and Henry Tuckerman n.d. (Box 6)
  - Fragments of Poems (author unknown) 1865, n.d. (Box 6)
- Scrapbooks
  - Scrapbook of printed material re Oaksmith Family (possibly kept by Augusta Oaksmith) ca. 1865-1880 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous material from Scrapbook #1 ca. 1865-1880 (Box 6)
  - Scrapbook of printed poems, articles and obituaries ca. 1870-1879 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous material from Scrapbook #2 ca. 1870-1879 (Box 6)
  - Scrapbook of printed poems n.d. (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous material from Scrapbook #3 n.d. (Box 6)
- Miscellaneous and Printed Material
  - Miscellaneous material n.d. (Box 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Review of Elizabeth Oakes Smith's plays 1849-1853 (Box 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings re: Astronomy 1851-1855 (Box 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Roupell vs Haws Court Case 1863 Jul (Box 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Biographical Material re Elizabeth Oakes Smith ca. 1880-1900 (Box 6)
  - Misc. Newspaper Clippings, 4 folders ca. 1850-1895, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Misc. Printed Material n.d. (Box 6)
  - Photographs and Drawings 1875-1885 (Box 6)